wallst.com 2017-12-31

# Markit.com | Privacy & Cookie Policy

Markit is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy applies to the personal information we collect on this website and the personal information we handle about the individual representatives (which term may include, without limitation, employees, officers or contractors) of our subscribers.

In addition, this privacy policy describes the type of information we gather and track, how the information is used, and with whom the information is shared.

In general, you can visit Markit on the internet without disclosing who you are or giving any personal information about yourself. There are times, however, when Markit may need information from you to better serve you.

For Markit’s advertising-related policies and consumer opt-out procedures, please see the [Markit On Demand Digital Advertising Privacy Policy](https://ad.wsod.com/privacy.php).

* * *

Markit collects personal information that you voluntarily provide on this website, which may include your name, address, e-mail address, and other contact information. For example, Markit collects personal information when you register to receive more information about certain Markit services or products and or when you submit the information in order to receive support for Markit services or products to which you subscribe. Markit uses this information to communicate with you and to provide you with your requested information or support.

If you are a representative of one of our subscribers, we may have received personal information about you from the subscriber (such as your name, work title and contact information). You also may provide us with your personal information directly in connection with your use of our offerings. This may include additional contact information, your date of birth, a copy of your passport (required by “know your customer” regulations), and payment information.

Markit primarily uses the personal information it collects to provide you with: (a) the services and data to which you are entitled; and (b) other information which you have requested. We also may use this personal information when analyzing and improving our services.

If you do not wish to provide such personal information to us, you are not obligated to, but as a result you may not be able to use our website or services. Some of the personal information we request from you is optional. This means that you can elect not to provide it to us and you still will be able to use our website or services. In most cases, we identify required personal information to you by displaying an asterisk (*) next to the field where we request the required personal information.

Markit may also provide you with information about our products and services. You may instruct Markit at any time not to use your personal information for this purpose by sending an email to [privacy@ihsmarkit.com](mailto:privacy@ihsmarkit.com).

A “tell-a-friend” or other similar sharing tool provided on our website and/or in our e-mails allows you to send information about our products and offerings to another person. When you use these tools, we may ask you for the name and information of the other person. That information will be covered by this privacy policy. We will use it only to send the communication to your friend and for no other purpose.

* * *

Markit uses reasonable administrative, technical, and physical measures: (a) to safeguard personal information against loss, theft, unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification; and (b) to ensure the integrity of the personal information. To help Markit protect your privacy, you should maintain the secrecy of the logon ID and password you may have set up in connection with your participation in the website or service.

From time to time Markit may supplement information you give Markit with information from other sources, such as information validating your address or other available information. This is to help Markit maintain the accuracy of the information it collects and to help Markit provide a better service.

* * *

Markit may store your personal information in its databases. The information may be retained and used by Markit for a reasonable period, reflecting Markit’s need to answer queries or resolve problems, provide new and improved services and any data retention requirements of the law.

Markit may retain information after the individual has ceased interacting with us. We retain this information when we have a business purpose to do so, such as user authentication or verification checks.

Thereafter, we will either delete your personal information or de-identify it so that it is anonymous and not attributed to your identity. Your right to request that we delete your personal information is set forth in the “Accuracy of your Personal Information; Your Access and Correction Rights” section below.

* * *

Markit may disclose your personal information to unaffiliated third parties if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary: (a) to comply with the law or in response to a court order, government request, or other legal process; (b) to protect the interests, rights, safety, or property of Markit or others; (c) to enforce any contract with you or our Subscriber who you represent, or any terms of service on this website; (d) to provide you with the services or products requested by you (including allowing a purchaser of a Markit division, or Markit as a whole, to continue to serve you), and to perform other activities related to such services and products, including billing and collection; (e) to provide you with information from Markit; or (f) to operate Markit's systems properly.

* * *

Markit sometimes collects non-identifiable information from visits to the website to help provide better customer service. Markit may use this data to analyse trends and statistics and to help provide better customer service.

Markit will collect such information through the use of various technologies, including "cookies". A cookie is an alphanumeric identifier that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser. The cookie may then be stored on your computer as an anonymous tag that identifies your computer but not you. You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You also can set your browser to turn off cookies. If you do so, some pages may not work properly and you do this at your own risk.

The “help” menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the website of its manufacturer.

Click for the list of cookies on Markit websites.

By using Markit’s website, you agree to our installation of these tracking technologies on your computer or device.

* * *

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website.

These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites, and the region of the country or world where your IP address indicates you are located, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These advertisements may appear on this website and on other websites. These companies may employ cookies, clear GIFs and other tracking technologies to cause relevant ads to be displayed to you.

We encourage you to read these businesses’ privacy policies to learn about how they treat your information. For more information about third-party advertisers and how to prevent them from using your information, visit the NAI’s consumer website at:

<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>

* * *

We encourage you to review, update and correct the personal information that we maintain about you, and you may request that we delete personal information about you that is inaccurate (or label it as such) by contacting us using the “Contact Us” information detailed in the “Contact Us” section below. By contacting us, you also may object to our further use of your personal information if you have compelling legitimate grounds (this may involve discontinuing your access to our services).

We may ask you to verify your identity and to provide other details before we are able to provide you with any information, correct any inaccuracies, or delete any information. We may charge you an administrative fee to process your request if doing so will require significant resources on our part, but we will inform you of the processing fee before we begin the work.

Your right to review, update, correct and delete your personal information may be limited: (i) if your requests are abusive or unreasonably excessive, (ii) where the burden or expense of providing you with these rights would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy, (iii) where the rights or safety of another person or persons would be encroached upon, or (iv) if the information or material you request relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings between you and us, or providing access to you would prejudice negotiations between us or an investigation of possible unlawful activity.

Your right to review, update, correct and delete your information is subject to our records retention policies and applicable law, including any statutory retention requirements.

* * *

Some of the uses and disclosures mentioned in this privacy policy may involve the transfer of your personal information to various countries around the world. By submitting your personal information via this website, you consent to such transfers.

* * *

Markit may provide links to third-party websites. Since Markit does not control third-party sites and is not responsible for any personal information you may provide while on such sites, Markit advises you to read the privacy policies on those websites before providing any of your personal information on such sites.

* * *

Markit may provide you with access to Markit services through links and/or dedicated frames (collectively, “Other Markit Services”). For example, you may have access to a Toolbar provided by our Hub service that allows you, amongst other things, to navigate data and content on both Markit and third party websites.

Your use of Other Markit Services shall be governed by any applicable terms of use and privacy policies. We recommend you review those before providing any personal information.

* * *

Markit reserves the right to change this privacy policy at any time by posting revisions on this web page. When we do, we will let you know by posting the changed privacy policy on this page with a new “Last Updated” date. Such changes will be effective upon posting. In some cases (for example, if we significantly expand our use or sharing of your personal information), we also may tell you about changes by additional means, such as by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address we have on file for you.

* * *

Any questions, concerns, or complaints concerning our collection and use of personal information should be directed to us at the address given below. We will conduct a reasonable investigation of and will attempt to resolve any complaints in accordance with the principles contained in this privacy policy.

* * *
